Portfolio Club Records
Portfolio Club Records
1875-2018
Portfolio Club (Syracuse, N.Y.)
15 linear ft.
Official records, historical files (clippings, correspondence); and publications, including programs and commemorative literature which documents the history of the organization. Official records include constitution and by-laws, minutes of meetings, etc.
150400
Organization History
The Portfolio Club is a women's organization that was founded in 1875 in Syracuse, New York.
" ... Women had little opportunity to meet and exchange ideas with other women except for an occasional tea, sewing group or church gathering.
"Responding to the plight of women in her day, Mary Dana Hicks, an art teacher in the Syracuse City Schools, attended a women's congress in 1875. Miss Hicks and her young art students were impressed by the speeches of such leading feminists as Mary Livermore, Mary Redfield Bagg, and Julia Ward Howe.
"Most impressive … was the appeal for women to organize into club groups and pursue whatever study or cause they considered important.
"Shortly after … a group of nine young high school girls met in October, 1875 … and formed a sketching club. The Portfolio Club, as it was called, was said to be one of the first women's clubs in Syracuse and one of the first in the nation. Although it was called the Portfolio Club because of the original study of art, it became more of a general interest club. Topics for study are assigned by the club president each year."
(Patricia Corbett, Syracuse Herald Journal, September 26, 1975)
Consisting of about 30 members, the club meets regularly from the first Monday in October to the second Monday in April. Each year new members are recommended and their admission to the club is voted upon by the current membership. Occasionally honorary members have also been selected. Club meetings are held at the homes of members or at local venues. A general topic, chosen by the President at the beginning of the program season, is broken down into a specific assignment for members to research and present on a designated date. Ranging over broad fields of interest, yearly topics have covered economics, religion, world culture, music, art, and science. Often characterized by inventive graphic design, which reflects the changing topics through decades of meeting seasons, programs document the club's officers and membership as well as the meeting schedules and their venues. The club is still active.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Portfolio Club Records comprises the historical files of the Syracuse, New York women's club. Beginning with the 1888-1889 program year, the meetings of the Portfolio Club have centered around an annual theme.
Arranged chronologically, the collection consists of the Club's incorporation papers, constitution and by-laws, clippings, correspondence, examination questions, memorial tributes, minutes, notes on lectures, annual programs, photographs, and some published material relating to the Club's history. Early minutes from the 1875 to 1884 are not among the Portfolio Club Records.
Memorabilia includes historical items and memorabilia related to the club but not part of the official records: photographs, clippings, material generated for an exhibit on the Portfolio Club in 2008, obituaries and memorial tributes, and so on.
Other Formats Available
The 8mm film in Box 6 has been digitized.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged in chronological order, apart from the supplemental material which is arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
See also the
Ida H. Bond Papers
. Ida Bond was a club member for many years in the early 1900s.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Women authors; Portfolio Club (Syracuse, N.Y.) -- Archives.; Portfolio Club (Syracuse, N.Y.) -- Records and correspondence.; Women -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Women -- Non-formal education.; Women -- Recreation.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- History.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; 8mm (photographic film size); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Essays.; Film reels.; Minutes (administrative records); Photographs.; Programs (documents); Sound recordings.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Portfolio Club and various club members.
Accruals
Additional material deposited annually.
Inventory
- 1875-1900
  - 1878 (Box 1)
    Certificate of incorporation (original and photocopy)
  - 1883 (Box 1)
    Examination questions
    Financial records and publicity for lecture by Francis Seymour Hayden, January 25, 1883
  - 1884-1885 (Box 1)
    Correspondence
  - 1884-1885,1890-1891 (Box 1)
    Lecture notes (Louise A. Stearns)
  - 1884-1886 (Box 1)
    Lecture notes (Mary E. Duguid)
  - 1887 (Box 1)
    Fire insurance policy
  - 1887-1890 (Box 1)
    Lecture notes and records of dues paid
  - 1888-1891 (Box 1)
    Lecture notes (Mary F. Hasbrouck)
  - Russia, 1888-1889 (Box 1)
    Clippings
  - French History, 1889-1890 (Box 1)
    Program booklet
  - Spain, 1890-1891 (Box 1)
  - North America, 1891-1892 (Box 1)
  - England, 1892-1893 (Box 1)
  - Studies in the History and Literature of Scotland, 1893-1894 (Box 1)
  - Rambles and Sketches in Holland, 1894-1895 (Box 1)
  - Under Our Own Root Tree - A Century of American Living and Thinking, 1895-1896 (Box 1)
    Minutes of meetings with clippings
  - 1896 (Box 2)
    Afternoons with Ceramics by Francis Hopkins Hooker
    Copyright certificate for Afternoons with Ceramics
  - Foot-Prints of the Old Masters, 1896-1897 (Box 2)
  - Nineteenth Century in Profile, 1897-1898 (Box 2)
  - "A New Chapter in American History," author unknown, 1898 (?) (Box 2)
  - Hellenic Gleanings, 1898-1899 (Box 2)
  - The Sunrise Empire: Japan, 1899-1900 (Box 2)
- 1900-1925
  See also the
  Ida Bond Papers (1900-1928)
  Ida Bond was a member of the Portfolio Club for many years.
  - Popular Questions of the Day, 1900-1901 (Box 2)
  - Notes on the history of the Portfolio Club (Helen Hudson Hood), 1901 (?) (Box 2)
  - Lines of Thought in the Victorian Era, 1901-1902 (Box 2)
  - India of Today, 1902-1903 (Box 3)
  - Round the World Tour, 1903-1904 (Box 3)
    Annual report
  - Germany in the Nineteenth Century, 1904-1905 (Box 3)
  - Woman in History, Literature, and Art, 1905-1906 (Box 3)
  - The Empire State, 1906-1907 (Box 3)
  - New York: Sights and Insights, 1907-1908 (Box 3)
  - Present Day Problems, 1908-1909 (Box 3)
  - Canada, 1909-1910 (Box 3)
  - The South, 1910-1911 (Box 3)
  - American Republics South of the United States, 1911-1912 (Box 3)
  - Egypt and Civic Problems of Today, 1912-1913 (Box 4)
  - The Bible: The World's Greatest Classic, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
  - Epochs and Epoch Makers of Christianity, 1914-1915 (Box 4)
  - Great American Achievements, 1915-1916 (Box 4)
  - The Development of International Relations of Europe, 1916-1917 (Box 4)
  - Westward Ho!, 1917-1918 (Box 4)
  - American Art Museums, 1918-1919 (Box 4)
  - New Problems in Democracy, 1919-1920 (Box 4)
  - Greater New York, 1920-1921 (Box 4)
  - A Study in Health, 1921-1922 (Box 4)
  - Glimpses into Many Lands through Travel, Literature, and History, 1922-1923 (Box 4)
  - China and the Chinese, 1923-1924 (Box 4)
  - Survey of a Quarter Century, 1924-1925 (Box 4)
- 1925-1950
  - Yesterday and Today: A Year of Retrospect and Outlook, 1925-1926 (Box 5)
  - The Portfolio Club: Our Fifty Years 1875-1925, 1926 (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Literature, 1926-1927 (Box 5)
  - Italian Art with Kindred Subjects, 1927-1928 (Box 5)
    Memorial tribute "To Mrs. Mary Dana Hicks Prang" by Grace A. Johnson
  - The Romance of Rivers, 1928-1929 (Box 5)
  - Leaders of American Thought, 1929-1930 (Box 5)
    Minutes of meetings
  - Our Heritage: A Study of Early American History in Relation to Present-day Problems, 1930-1931 (Box 5)
  - What Price Progress: A Study of Current American Problems, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - What Men Live By, 1932-1933 (Box 5)
  - This New Leisure, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - Africa in the Twentieth Century, 1934-1935 (Box 6)
  - Journeys on the Hobby Horse, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
    (portfolio_001) 8mm film taken at the home of Mrs. Henry Phillips, October 1935
  - These United States: Foundations and Functions of Government with Allied Subjects, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
  - Mankind Fares as the Pioneer Dares, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - The Development of the English Novel, 1938-1939 (Box 6)
  - American Exports, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
    Photograph "Portfolio Club Christmas Play" (1939) by Preston Mitchell
  - New Horizons in Living, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Western Hemisphere, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - The Constant Goal, 1942-1943 (Box 7)
  - Peace-Times in War-Times, 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Golden Ages in the Development of Our Country, 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - The Portfolio Club: Our Ten Years 1935-1945 by Louise K. French, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Russia - 'The Great Fact', 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - China, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Significant Trends in American Life and Thought, 1947-1948 (Box 7)
  - Music Hath Charms, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
  - Let Freedom Ring, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
- 1950-1975
  - This Is Our Century, What Shall We Make of It?, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - The International Pattern, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - The American Woman: The Feminine Side of a Masculine Civilization, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - The World Around Us, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Great Books, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - "The Portfolio Club 1945-1955: The Years of Search" by Preston Settle Mitchell, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Men of Religion, 1955-1956 (Box 8)
  - The Theatre - A Living Art, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
  - The Flowering of Our Prose Masters: A Literary Renaissance, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - The Indians of the Americas, 1958-1959 (Box 8)
  - Profiles of Our Present Day Janus, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Africa in the Modern World, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - The World Within: A Study of Human Personality, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - What Is Art?, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Italy, 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Saints & Sinners, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - The Opera... A Mirror of Its Time, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - A Potpourri of Art Forms, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Classical Greece - Our Heritage, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Financial records, 1968-1996 (Box 9)
  - Some Enchanted Islands, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Communication: The Most Important Business of Man and Beast, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
    Minutes of meetings (incomplete)
  - Change in the Twentieth Century or Questions Portfolians Ask in a Turbulent Period of History, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - The Restless Emerald, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - New York - Our State: People, Places, and Happenings of Interest to Its History, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    Program presentations: Feb. 19 - "Pioneer Years of Syracuse University"
  - Israel, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    Minutes of meetings, president's agendas
    Program presentations: Feb. 18 - "Economic, Cultural, and Governmental Achievements of Israel"
  - Portfolio: Retrospect and Expectation, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    President's agendas, annual report
    Photograph
  - One Hundredth Birthday Party, 1975 (Box 10)
    Guest book
    "Portfolio Club: A Goodly Heritage 1875-1975"
- 1975-2000
  - Parapsychology, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
    Minutes of meetings, annual report
  - People Make the Difference, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    Program presentations: Feb. 28 - "Mary McLeod Bethune"
  - Ethnicity in America - The Challenge of Diversity, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - Humor in American Literature: The Most Elusive of the Arts, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Contemporary American Religious Movements: New Vessels for the Ancient Wisdom, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    Program booklet, president's introduction
    Program presentations: Mar. 17 - "Unification Church"
  - Profiles of the Oriental Mind: China and Japan, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Around the World in Eighty Ways, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - The Political History of Canada Seen through the Lives of Its Prime Ministers, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    Notes
  - The Political History of Canada Seen through the Lives of Its Prime Ministers (cont.), 1982-1983 (Oversize 2)
    Pastel portrait of John D. MacDonald, by Betty Maltby
  - Courageous People and Their Adventures, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - The World of Islam, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Quality of Life in the 21st Century: A 2020 Vision, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
    Program presentations:
    Oct. 7 - Family Life
    Oct. 21 - Work Places
    Nov. 4 - Health Care
    Nov. 18 - Education
    Dec. 2 - The Older Americans
    Jan. 20 - Housing
    Feb. 3 - Cities
    Feb. 17 - Environment
    Mar. 3 - Societal Dropouts
    Mar. 17 - Leisure Time
    Apr. l 7 - Communication
  - Middle America: A Mosaic of Peoples, Places, and Cultures, 1986-1987 (Box 11)
    Program booklet, president's intro
  - Great Rivers of the World: Their Contribution to Our Cultural Heritage, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
  - The Designing of America: An Evolutionary Process of History, the Architecture of Society, Man's Ingenuity as the Driving Force, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
  - Creators of Art in America, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
    President's agendas
  - Environmental Citizenship: Some Insights; Some Issues; Some Ideas, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
    Guest Day Committee report
    Oct. 1 - A Native American Speaks
    Oct. 15 - Form & Pattern; Time & Rhythm
    Nov. 19 - Migration
    Feb. 4 - Endangered Species
    Feb. 18 - The Land - Conservation; Restoration
    Mar. 4 - Environmental Study: Teaching Our Youth
    Mar. 18 - International Solutions; Joint Initiatives
  - Legendary Faces, Legendary Places: Legend as Man's Link with the Past, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    (portfolio_002) audio tape "First Meeting 1991-92"
    Oct. 21 - Princess Elissa - Founder of Carthage
    Nov. 4 - King Minos of Crete
    Nov. 18 - The Search for Troy
    Dec. 2 - Atlantis, the Fantasy Island
    Dec. 16 - A Legendary Christmas
    Jan. 20 - Babylon the Great
    Feb. 8 - Brendan the Navigator
    Mar. 2 - Boudissa, the Warrior Queen
    Mar. 16 - The Romance of Arthur
  - Resetting the American Table", 1992-1993 (Box 12)
    Oct. 5 - Revisiting the Basics
    Oct. 19 - Food Habits Around the World
    Dec. 7 - Safe at the Plate
    Dec. 21 - Critique - Cookbooks, Recipes
    Feb. 1 - Veggies
    Feb. 15 - Minerals Women Need Most
    Mar. 1 - Grandma Called It Roughage
    Mar. 15 - Feeding the Kids Isn't Easy
    Apr. 5 - Flowering Delights, Lawn Food, Herbs and Spices
  - Reforming Our Health Care Delivery System, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    President's introduction and notes
    Oct. 4 - Our Present Health Care Delivery System
    Oct. 18 - Payors for Health Care Delivery
    Nov. 15 - Providers of Health Care
    Dec. 6 - Long Term Care
    Dec. 20 - Celebrating Good Health
    Jan. 17 - The Right to Die
    Feb. 21 - Jane and John Q. Public's Relationship to the New System
    Mar. 7 - The Role of Medicines in Health Care
    Mar. 21 - Is Managed Competition the Route to Go?
    Apr. 4 - The Projected U.S. Health Care Reform Plan
  - Selected Operatic Women Characters, Are They Our Sisters?, 1994-1995 (Box 13)
    Oct. 3 - Lucia
    Oct. 17 - Gilda
    Nov. 7 - Violetta
    Nov. 21 - Selika
    Dec. 5 - Carmen
    Feb. 6 - Nedda
    Mar. 20 - Princess Turandot
    Apr. 3 - Bess
  - The Pacific Rim", 1995-1996 (Box 13)
    Nov. 20 - Thailand
    Dec. 4 - Vietnam
    Oct. 2 - Indonesia
    Mar. 18 - China
    Apr. 1 - Japan
  - Ten Trials of the Century: Was Justice Served?, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    Oct. 7 - Sacco & Vanzetti
    Oct. 21 - Scopes - Monkey Trial
    Nov. 4 - The Lindberg Kidnapping Case
    Nov. 18 - The Nuremberg Trial
    Dec 2 - The Rosenberg Case
    Jan. - The Sheppard Trial
    Feb. 3 - The Chicago Seven Cospiracy Trial
    Feb 17 - The Trial of Patty Hearst
    Mar 3 - The Charles Manson trial
    Mar. 17 - The O.J. Simpson Trial
    Apr. 7 - Summary of Findings and Conclusion to the Study
  - Through the Eyes of a Child, 1997-1998 (Box 13-14)
    President's introduction, notes, report
    Corresponding secretary files
    Oct. 6 - History of Children's Literature
    Oct. 20 - Artists and Their Illustrations
    Nov. 3 - Picture Books
    Nov. 17 - Traditional Literature
    Dec. 15 - Christmas - The Legend of St. Nicholas and the Christmas Story
    Jan. 19 - Children's Poetry
    Feb. 2 - Contemporary Realistic Fiction
    Mar. 2 - Multicultural Children's Literature
    Mar. 16 - Nonfiction: Biographies, Informational Books
    Apr. 6 - Award Books / Censorship
  - The New Global Economy, 1998-1999; 12 folders (Box 14)
    President's introduction
    Correspondence (including poem by Betty Maltby)
    Historian's report
    Oct. 5 - History of Economics
    Oct. 19 - Unplanned Forces Which Led to a New System
    Nov. 2 - The International Monetary Fund
    Nov. 16 - The European Union
    Dec. 7 - Regional Alliances: Cultural Complications
    Dec. 21 - Portfolio Christmas Program
    Jan. 18 - Asia: a Single Nation & Trading Bloc
    Feb. 1 - Implications for the Future of Education and Work
    Mar. 1 - Global Consumerism
    Mar. 15 - The Biggest Global Business of All
    Apr. 5 - Short-Term Predictions, Long-Term Implications
  - The Nations 2000, 1999-2000; 12 folders (Box 14)
    Minutes
    Oct. 4 - Pre-History
    Oct. 18 - Contact History 1492-1974
    Nov. 1 - Science, Math, Health
    Nov. 15 - Education
    Dec. 6 - Economics and Gambling
    Jan. 17 - Culture: Arts, Religion, Environment
    Feb. 21 - Government
    Mar. 6 - An Indian Woman
    Mar. 20 - The Iroquois Nation to 1974
    Apr. 3 - The Oneida Indian Land Claim: Long-term Implications
- 2000-2025
  - A Celebration of Women, 2000-2001 (Box 14-15)
    Oct. 2 - A Celebration - 125 Years
    Oct. 16 - The Ceramics Collection at the Everson Museum
    Nov. 6 - Eleanor Roosevelt (1884-1962)
    Nov. 20 - Margaret Sanger (1879-1966); Marie Curie (1867-1934
    Dec. 4 - Golda Meir (1898-1978)
    Dec. 18 - Celebrating Christmas
    Jan. 15 - Women of Words
    Feb. 5 - Women Who Focus on Life
    Feb. 19 - The Medieval Women
    Mar. 5 - Women in Law
    Apr. 2 - Mother Teresa (1910-1997)
  - Angels, Goddesses, and Witches, 2001-2002; 14 folders (Box 15)
    Oct. 1 - Heralding the Angels
    Oct. 15 - Angels in America
    Nov. 5 - Angels in the Information Age
    Nov. 19 - Poles Apart: Empirical Angels at the Fin de Siècle
    Dec. 3 - The Great Goddess
    Dec. 19 - A Celebration of the Season with Angels
    Jan. 21 - The Goddesses Within
    Feb. 18 - The Double Helix
    Mar. 4 - The History of Witchcraft
    Mar. 18 - Ritual Belief: Theory and Practice
    Apr. 1 - The Witches Among Us
  - Understanding the Brain: History and Mystery Revealed, 2002-2003; 16 folders (Box 15)
    Historian's report; invocation by Mary Ten Eyck
    Oct. 7 - Early Explorers of the Nervous System
    Oct. 21 - Nineteenth Century Researchers of the Brain
    Nov. 4 - The Twentieth Century: An Explosion of Knowledge
    Nov. 18 - Steven Pinker's 'The Language Instinct'
    Dec. 2 - The Five Senses: Sight, Sound, Smell, Touch & Taste
    Dec. 16 - A Christmas Portfolio Program of Song, Dance, and Verse
    Jan. 20 - The Emotions
    Feb. 3 - Memory
    Feb. 17 - 'To Sleep? Perchance to Dream...' Sigmund Freud and the State of Psychoanalysis
    Mar. 3 - Reassessing Psychiatry in the 21st Century: Treating the Dysfunctional Mind
    Mar. 17 - Intelligence
    Apr. 7 - Consciousness and the Mind/Brain Controversy
    Apr. 28 - President's luncheon
  - Seeking Peace, 2003-2004; 3 folders (Box 17)
    Oct. 6 - Hiroshima and Nagasaki
    Oct. 20 - South Africa
    Nov. 3 - The Cold War
    Nov. 17 - The Middle East
    Dec. 1 - Jerusalem
    Dec. 15 - Let There Be Peace
    Jan. 19 - Northern Ireland: The Troubles
    Feb. 2 - 'The Peace Movement
    Feb. 17 - The Nobel Peace Prize
    Mar. 1 - The Peace Corps
    Mar. 15 - The United Nations
    Apr. 5 - A Reflection
    Apr. 26 - President's luncheon
  - The World of Music, 2004-2005; 4 folders (Box 17)
    Program presentations, includes CD of musical exerpts:
    Oct. 4 - The Early Roots of Music (no representations exist)
    Oct. 18 - Medieval Music
    Nov. 1 - Music of the Renaissance
    Nov. 15 - Music of the Far East
    Dec. 6 - African Music
    Dec. 20 - Christmas program (guest performers Laura Enslin and Sar Shalom Strong)
    Jan. 17 - Early Music of Black America
    Feb. 7 - 'Great Symphonies and their Conductors
    Feb. 21 - Rock and Roll
    Mar. 7 - Music of the Baroque Era
    Mar. 21 - Protest and Folk Music
    Apr. 4 - Hip Hop and Rap
    Apr. 18(25) - President's luncheon
  - Trading: From the Silk Road to the Electronic Highway, 2005-2006; 4 folders (Box 17)
    Program booklet (includes list of presidents back to the 1970s, and projected presidents through 2024)
    Oct. 3 - The Silk Road
    Oct. 17 - Traders on the Sea
    Nov. 7 - The Human Trade
    Nov. 21 - Trade Passages
    Dec. 5 - Great Trades
    Dec. 19 - Trading of Gifts
    Jan. 16 - Trading Sites
    Feb. 6 - Famous Traders
    Feb. 20 - Emerging Markets of Trade
    Mar. 6 - Trading Instruments / Trading Regulation
    Mar. 20 - The Electronic Highway
    Apr. 3 - The Psychology of Trading Up
    Apr. 18 - President's luncheon
  - I am Woman — Who am I?, 2006-2007; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Correspondence (including Dianna Winslow)
    Oct. 2 - Menses, Menopause and More...The Physical
    Oct. 16 - The Fountain of Youth: Life Begins at 60
    Nov. 6- A Woman's Health
    Nov. 20 - Women and Leadership in Government and Business
    Dec. 4 - Women as Role Models: Fashion, Media, Entertainment, Sports
    Dec. 18 - Motherhood: A Celebration of Mothers, Mothering, and Mary
    Jan. 15 - Mother-Daughter Relationships
    Feb. 5 - Women Empowering Women in our World
    Feb. 19 - Women and Philanthropy
    Mar. 5 - Women in the Workplace
    Mar. 19 - People, Places, and Things Which Inspire Us
    Apr. 2 - This & That: Hints, Tips, Wives' Tales, Discoveries and Advice
    Apr. 17 - President's luncheon
  - Nature's Voice: Humankind's Standpoint, 2007-2008; 4 folders (Box 18)
    Photographs from Christmas party
    Oct. 1 - Forefathers and Foremothers of the Modern Environmental Movement
    Oct. 15 - Early Government Intervention and Environmental Organizations
    Nov. 5 - Endangered Species
    Nov. 19 - Clean Water
    Dec. 3 - Clean Air: Thank You for Not Smoking
    Dec. 17 - In the Bleak Midwinter: Nature from the Standpoint of Faith Groups
    Jan. 21 - China: Is the Standpoint Different?
    Feb. 4 - American's Throwaway Culture: How We Deal With Our Garbage
    Feb. 18 - What Happened to Onondaga Lake?
    Mar. 3 - A Brief History of Alternative Fuel Sources: What Lies Ahead
    Mar. 17 - Recent Changes in our Environment: What's CO2 Got to Do With It?
    Apr. 7 - So Where Do We Go From Here: The Economics of Going Green
    Apr. 21 - President's luncheon
  - Collecting: Museums and Otherwise, 2008-2009; 4 folders (Box 18-19)
    Treasurer's report
    Oct. 6 - The Smithsonian
    Oct. 20 - Metropolitan Museum of Art
    Nov. 3 - Specialty Collections
    Nov. 17 - Preserving Early America
    Dec. 1 - Commemorating Tragedy
    Dec. 15 - Collecting Christmas
    Jan. 19 - Everson Museum of Art
    Feb. 2 - Roadside Attractions
    Feb. 16 - What Portfolians Collect (includes original binder with photographs)
    Mar. 2 - Curator vs Hoarder
    Mar. 16 - Museum Architecture: Art or Fortress?
    Apr. 6 - CNY's Specialty Collections
  - Our Supreme Court, 2009-2010; 5 folders (Box 19)
    Correspondence and notes
    Oct. 5 - Framing the Judicial Branch
    Oct. 19 - John Marshall
    Nov. 2 - Roger Taney
    Nov. 16 - The Supreme Court in Wartime
    Dec. 7 - Troubles for the White House
    Dec. 21 - The Process / Holiday Celebration